Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Ct Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

Applications Engineer for Computer Controlled Equipment

Experienced software engineer and applications engineer supporting customers and writing computer code shared among customers of Automated Test Equipment (ATE).

Software responsibility included developing and maintaining a dynamically loadable library (.dll) under Microsoft .net and a shared object (.so) under UNIX. This project was over 100K lines of code and was ported across four computer operating systems.

The success of the software project depended on the extensive documentation (Frame/HTML) and ftp site distribution to customers all over the world. The fun part of this software project was the installations on semiconductor production floors across the world. This often involved project oriented customer and vendor meetings.

Software OS and Tools

.Net/Visual Studio/Codecenter SourceSafe/make/ClearCase/SCCS Framemaker/PDF Serial (RS232), IEEE488 (GPIB) communications National Instruments GPIB analyzer Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point) Windows XP/NT UNIX/Solaris/SunOS DNS/NFS TCP/IP & RDP communications UNIX system administration Oracle

Computer Languages

C/C++ bourne/csh shell scripts LISP PASCAL SQL/RPL Modula-2, PL/1, FORTRAN

Engineering Applications

Communications Driver development Real-Time Programming Data processing (ASCII & STDF) Software Test Procedures VLSI testing Production Floor Process
Compiler Techniques
VLSI Pattern Conversion
Circuit Testing
Semiconductor Processing

Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Ct Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer – Credence Systems Corp., Fremont, CA 1991-1992 & 1996-2005

- From coding through the build, archive and distribution process, maintained about 30 intelligent prober and handler communications drivers for Credence testers.
- Created a 150 page document describing the prober and handler communications and customer installation and usage.
- Improve production throughput up to 100% through monitored production floor performance on Credence manufactured ATE testers.
- Install, test and assist customers worldwide in automation on their test floor.
- Supplied simple parallel (TTL) cable implementations, design and debug for test floor prober and handler production automation.
- Ported a Graphical User Interface from a SUN 3 based architecture to a SPARC
 architecture. This included resolving porting problems such as data structure
 incompatibility in RPC packets and SunView programming errors.

Customer Support Engineer – TeamOne Systems Inc., Sunnyvale, CA 1992-1994

- Provided 800 number customer support for configuration management software. TeamOne's system is a kernel based file system. Support entails knowing UNIX file systems, NFS and system administration.
- Developed call tracking software package facilitation call follow up and allowing statistical measurements on incoming calls servicing.

Applications Engineer – Teradyne Inc., Sunnyvale, CA

1989-1991

- Provided post sales support for the Semiconductor CIM Division FIRMS product line. This included integrating information from VLSI test systems into an Oracle data base for later RS/1 analysis.
- Taught the training classes for the Teradyne configured data base and graphics tools. Rewrote into Framemaker the User's and Manager's training course material.

EDUCATION

Carnegie-Mellon University, PGH, PA

BS in Mathematics, emphasis in CS and EE